<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shreyash Somvanshi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shreyash Somvanshi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:15:59 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neural Machine Translation &amp; Translation Metrics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/neural-machine-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/neural-machine-translation/</guid>
      <description> Topics Covered: Neural Machine Translation Translation Metrics: BLEU Score &amp;amp; BERT Score Applications </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/me/</guid>
      <description>About ME! Hello and welcome to my corner of the internet! I&amp;rsquo;m Shreyash, an aspiring Data Scientist and AI Engineer with a passion for Data. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share my journey, insights, and experiences with you.&#xA;With a background in Artificial Intelligence and Data Science, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of diving deep into the world of Data Science. From innovative projects, I&amp;rsquo;ve honed my skills in Python, Machine Learning, Data Science and I&amp;rsquo;m constantly seeking new ways to push the boundaries of what&amp;rsquo;s possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthcheck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/talk/synthcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/talk/synthcheck/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to give this talk! Stay tuned for video and slides.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 01:00:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.&#xA;Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable A.I.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/certification/explainable-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/certification/explainable-ai/</guid>
      <description>&#xA;Learnings: The Importance of Human Interpretable Machine Learning Model Interpretation Strategies LIME (Local Interpretable Model-agnostic Explanations) SHAP (SHapley Additive exPlanations) Other Explainable AI Tools ELI5 Skater What-If Tool Azure ML The Future of Interpretability Enroll for free: https://aiplanet.com/learn/explainable-ai </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SynthCheck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/synthcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/synthcheck/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:&#xA;Welcome to our Synthcheck: A Synthetic Image Identification using Deep Learning project! Our project aims to develop a system capable of detecting synthetic or manipulated images using advanced deep learning techniques, while also providing explanations for model predictions. Objective:&#xA;Develop a deep learning model to classify images as either real or synthetic based on their visual characteristics. Incorporate explainable AI techniques to provide insights into the model&amp;rsquo;s decision-making process and highlight features indicative of synthetic images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCI Certified Data Science Professional</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/certification/oci-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/certification/oci-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Learnings: OCI Data Science - Introduction &amp;amp; Configuration Discuss OCI Data Science Overview &amp;amp; Concepts Understand the capabilities of Accelerated Data Science(ADS) SDK Configure your tenancy for Data Science Design and Set up OCI Data Science Workspace Create and manage Projects and Notebook sessions Create and manage Conda environments Store credentials via OCI Vault Configure and manage source code in Code Repositories (Git) Implement end-to-end Machine Learning Lifecycle Discuss ML Lifecycle Overview Access data from different sources Explore and Prepare data Visualize and Profile data Create and train models using OCI and Open source Libraries Create and Use automated ML capability from Oracle AutoML Evaluate models Obtain Global &amp;amp; Local Model Explanations Manage models using Model Catalog Deploy &amp;amp; Invoke a Cataloged Model Apply MLOps Practices Understand OCI MLOps Architecture Create &amp;amp; Manage Jobs for custom tasks Scale with OCI Data Science Monitor &amp;amp; Log using MLOps Practices Use Pipelines to automate machine learning workflow Use related OCI Services Create and Manage Spark Applications using Data Flow and OCI Data Science Understand OCI Open Data Service Create and Export a Dataset using OCI Data Labeling Use OCI AI Services for ML Solutions Course Link: https://education.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Dashboard on U.S. Car Failure Data using RMd</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/interactive-dashboard-rmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/interactive-dashboard-rmd/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:&#xA;Welcome to the Car Failure Dataset Dashboard Project! Objective: Analyze and visualize data related to car failures to provide insights into common issues and trends. Dataset Source: Obtained from [source], includes information about car failures over a specific period. Dashboard Overview:&#xA;Purpose: Interactive exploration of the car failure dataset through visualizations and filters. Key Features: Dynamic filtering by car make, model, failure type, and visualization of trends over time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coursify: A Course Recommendation System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/course-recommend-sys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/course-recommend-sys/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:&#xA;Welcome to our Course Recommendation System Project! Our system assists users in finding relevant courses based on their interests and preferences. Objective:&#xA;Develop a recommendation system to enhance users&amp;rsquo; learning experience by suggesting courses tailored to their needs. Dataset Description:&#xA;Utilized a dataset containing course information such as titles, descriptions, categories, and user ratings. Sourced the dataset from [source], a platform specializing in online courses. Data Preprocessing:&#xA;Cleaned the dataset, handled missing values, and transformed categorical variables for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python for Data Science - Corise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/certification/corise-py-datasci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/certification/corise-py-datasci/</guid>
      <description>&#xA;Learnings: Python Basics Data Pre-processing Data Modeling Numpy Pandas Scikit learn Streamlit </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute to Open Source? (For Beginners)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/contribute-to-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/contribute-to-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to open source is a great way to learn, teach, and build experience in any skill.&#xA;First of all you must be familiar with basic Git/GitHub functionalities (i.e. What is commit, repository, fork, branches, merging, merge conflicts, etc).&#xA;Improve the software you rely on! Improve existing skills. Meet and build a network of people having similar interests as like you. Find mentors or teach others. Build public artifacts to build a reputation and career.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a simple and attractive Contact form for your website without PHP!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/contact-form-without-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/contact-form-without-php/</guid>
      <description>Contact form is an essential feature of any website. Every website has a contact form to receive some important feedback or suggestions from their potential visitors or customers.&#xA;Generally, contact forms are made responsive using PHP. But here I will show you simplest way to create an attractive form using only HTML and CSS ! You can find its source code here.&#xA;The most important factors of any contact forms are GET and POST requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Market Segmentation of Electric Vehicles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/ev-market-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/ev-market-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:&#xA;Welcome to our EV Market Segmentation Project! Our project aims to segment the electric vehicle market based on various demographic, geographic, and psychographic factors to better understand consumer preferences and behavior. Objective:&#xA;Develop a segmentation model to categorize electric vehicle consumers into distinct groups or segments based on their characteristics. Explore the diverse needs, preferences, and motivations of different consumer segments within the EV market. Dataset Description:&#xA;Utilized a dataset containing demographic information, purchase behavior, geographical location, and other relevant attributes of electric vehicle consumers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing or Uninstalling R on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/r-install-uninstall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/r-install-uninstall/</guid>
      <description>R is a open source programming language for statistical computing and graphics supported by the R Core Team and the R Foundation for Statistical Computing. Created by statisticians Ross Ihaka and Robert Gentleman, R is used among data miners, bioinformaticians and statisticians for data analysis and developing statistical software. Users have created packages to augment the functions of the R language. According to user surveys and studies of scholarly literature databases, R is one of the most commonly used programming languages used in data mining.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Julia and Configuring it in Jupyter Notebook.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/julia-install-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/julia-install-config/</guid>
      <description>Julia is a Fast, Dynamic, Reproducible, Composable, Open Source programming language. It has its applications in Data Science, Machine Learning, Parallel Computing, other Scientific domains.&#xA;So to install latest version of Julia on Ubuntu you can follow just the few steps given below.&#xA;Step 1: Open your terminal and change the directory to Downloads.&#xA;$ cd ~/Downloads&#xA;Step 2: Use wget to download the latest compressed Julia Linux Binaries:&#xA;$ wget https://julialang-s3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis using NLP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/sentiment-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/sentiment-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:&#xA;Welcome to our Sentiment Analysis Project! Our project aims to analyze the sentiment of text data to understand public opinion, feedback, or emotions expressed in various contexts. Objective:&#xA;Develop a sentiment analysis model to automatically classify text data into positive, negative, or neutral sentiments. Explore how sentiment analysis can be applied to social media posts, product reviews, or customer feedback to gain valuable insights. Dataset Description:&#xA;Utilized a dataset containing text data, such as social media posts, customer reviews, or movie reviews, labeled with sentiment labels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database Management Systems - NPTEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/certification/dbms-nptel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/certification/dbms-nptel/</guid>
      <description>&#xA;Learnings: Introduction to RDBMS Structured Query Language (SQL) Relational Algebra. Entity-Relationship Model Relational Database Design Application Development. Case Studies. Storage and File Structure Indexing and Hashing. Query Processing Query Optimization. Transactions (Serializability and Recoverability) Concurrency Control. Recovery Systems. Course Link: https://onlinecourses.nptel.ac.in/noc22_cs91/preview </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Data Analytics - Coursera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/certification/google-data-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/certification/google-data-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&#xA;Learnings: Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere Ask Questions to Make Data-Driven Decisions Prepare Data for Exploration Process Data from Dirty to Clean Analyze Data to Answer Questions Share Data Through the Art of Visualization Data Analysis with R Programming Course Link: https://www.coursera.org/professional-certificates/google-data-analytics </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phishing Website Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/phishing-website-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/phishing-website-detection/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:&#xA;Welcome to our Phishing Website Detection Project! Our project aims to develop a system capable of automatically detecting phishing websites to enhance online security. Objective:&#xA;Develop a machine learning model to classify websites as legitimate or phishing based on their characteristics. Explore the use of features such as URL structure, domain age, SSL certificates, and website content to identify potential phishing attempts. Dataset Description:&#xA;Utilized a dataset containing labeled examples of legitimate and phishing websites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R Essentials for Data Science - IBM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/certification/r-essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/certification/r-essentials/</guid>
      <description>&#xA;Learnings: R basics Data structures in R R programming fundamentals Working with data in R Strings and Dates in R Course link: https://cognitiveclass.ai/courses/r-101 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Basics for Data Science - edX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/certification/edx-py-datasci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/certification/edx-py-datasci/</guid>
      <description>&#xA;Learnings: Python Basics Python Data Structures Python Programming Fundamentals Working with Data in Python Working with Numpy Arrays Course Link: https://www.edx.org/learn/python/ibm-python-basics-for-data-science </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using panelsets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/seedling/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of panelset.js by Garrick Aden-Buie, from his xaringanExtra package: https://pkg.garrickadenbuie.com/xaringanExtra/#/panelset&#xA;For example, this panelset:&#xA;Hello! &amp;#x1f44b; hello&#xA;Goodbye &amp;#x1f4a8; goodbye&#xA;Was created by combining this theme&amp;rsquo;s panelset and panel shortcodes:&#xA;{{&amp;lt; panelset class=&amp;#34;greetings&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Hello! :wave:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} hello {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Goodbye :dash:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} goodbye {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; /panelset &amp;gt;}} You could also revert to HTML as well. For example, this panelset:&#xA;Question Which came first: the :chicken: or the :egg:?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:&#xA;Desirée De Leon &amp;#x1f992; (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)&#xA;Garrick Aden-Buie &amp;#x1f9d9; (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)&#xA;Allison Horst &amp;#x1f415; (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot &amp;#x1f994;)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/privacypolicy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/privacypolicy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy This Privacy Policy outlines how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit this website. By accessing or using the website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.&#xA;1. Information We Collect&#xA;Contact Form: When you submit information through the contact form, we collect your name and email address to respond to your inquiry.&#xA;Newsletter: If you subscribe to our newsletter, we collect your email address to provide updates and relevant content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terms and Conditions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/terms/</guid>
      <description>Terms and Conditions Welcome to this website! By accessing and using this website, you agree to comply with these terms and conditions. If you disagree with any part of these terms, please refrain from using the website.&#xA;Website Rights Attribution: The rights to this open-source Hugo Apero template belong to its core contributors and developers, and I acknowledge and respect their creative contributions.&#xA;Content Ownership: Unless specified otherwise, most of the content on this website belongs to owner.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
