<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BLOGS on Shreyash Somvanshi</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BLOGS on Shreyash Somvanshi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute to Open Source? (For Beginners)</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/contribute-to-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/contribute-to-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to open source is a great way to learn, teach, and build experience in any skill.&#xA;First of all you must be familiar with basic Git/GitHub functionalities (i.e. What is commit, repository, fork, branches, merging, merge conflicts, etc).&#xA;Improve the software you rely on! Improve existing skills. Meet and build a network of people having similar interests as like you. Find mentors or teach others. Build public artifacts to build a reputation and career.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a simple and attractive Contact form for your website without PHP!</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/contact-form-without-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/contact-form-without-php/</guid>
      <description>Contact form is an essential feature of any website. Every website has a contact form to receive some important feedback or suggestions from their potential visitors or customers.&#xA;Generally, contact forms are made responsive using PHP. But here I will show you simplest way to create an attractive form using only HTML and CSS ! You can find its source code here.&#xA;The most important factors of any contact forms are GET and POST requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing or Uninstalling R on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/r-install-uninstall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/r-install-uninstall/</guid>
      <description>R is a open source programming language for statistical computing and graphics supported by the R Core Team and the R Foundation for Statistical Computing. Created by statisticians Ross Ihaka and Robert Gentleman, R is used among data miners, bioinformaticians and statisticians for data analysis and developing statistical software. Users have created packages to augment the functions of the R language. According to user surveys and studies of scholarly literature databases, R is one of the most commonly used programming languages used in data mining.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Julia and Configuring it in Jupyter Notebook.</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/julia-install-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/julia-install-config/</guid>
      <description>Julia is a Fast, Dynamic, Reproducible, Composable, Open Source programming language. It has its applications in Data Science, Machine Learning, Parallel Computing, other Scientific domains.&#xA;So to install latest version of Julia on Ubuntu you can follow just the few steps given below.&#xA;Step 1: Open your terminal and change the directory to Downloads.&#xA;$ cd ~/Downloads&#xA;Step 2: Use wget to download the latest compressed Julia Linux Binaries:&#xA;$ wget https://julialang-s3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using panelsets</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/seedling/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of panelset.js by Garrick Aden-Buie, from his xaringanExtra package: https://pkg.garrickadenbuie.com/xaringanExtra/#/panelset&#xA;For example, this panelset:&#xA;Hello! &amp;#x1f44b; hello&#xA;Goodbye &amp;#x1f4a8; goodbye&#xA;Was created by combining this theme&amp;rsquo;s panelset and panel shortcodes:&#xA;{{&amp;lt; panelset class=&amp;#34;greetings&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Hello! :wave:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} hello {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Goodbye :dash:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} goodbye {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; /panelset &amp;gt;}} You could also revert to HTML as well. For example, this panelset:&#xA;Question Which came first: the :chicken: or the :egg:?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
