<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Streamlit on Shreyash Somvanshi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/categories/streamlit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Streamlit on Shreyash Somvanshi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/categories/streamlit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Course Recommendation System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/course-recommend-sys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/course-recommend-sys/</guid>
      <description>🔗 GitHub Description The aim of the project is to build an open-source quadcopter platform for research in the field of drone autonomy. Various deep learning and computer vision algorithms will be implemented on the drone including person tracking, gesture control using human pose estimation, optical flow stabilization, obstacle avoidance, and depth estimation using monocular vision. The drone uses a Pixhawk flight controller with Raspberry Pi as a companion computer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis using NLP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/sentiment-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/sentiment-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Tachyons is a design system that allows you to design gorgeous interfaces in the browser with little effort. Because Speed Building this static site generator theme was the first time I used an Atomic (or Functional) CSS system like Tachyons. It&amp;rsquo;s a design system that provides very small (which means fast) CSS modules that you can use in your HTML. So, rather than writing every line of CSS, you apply the style you need as you write your HTML with easy to understand shorthand class names.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
